# **Darren** Labithiotis

## Remote Senior Software Engineer

darren@labithiotis.com (+44) 7545 615129 Alexanderhofstraße 36, Millstatt, 9872, Austria

A passionate software engineer, with over 8+ years of experience. Skills ranging from single-page apps to full-stacks, and mobile apps. Have used various libraries over the years and learnt from best practices. The current preferred stack involves; Typescript, React, React Native, Sass/Less, Redux, Node, Express/Koa, GraphQL, MongoDB or PostgresSQL.

Before becoming a software engineer I studied as a game designer, thus am proficient in design. These skills, combined with my coding ability, help deliver projects to a high standard and have a keen eye for user experience.

In 2017 I relocated to the Austrian mountains, moving away from central London where I'd worked for 10 years. As such I work as a full-time remote contractor. Working remotely genuinely allows one to be more focused with fewer distractions, and with today's technology, it's easy to attend meetings, daily stand-ups and pair program as if co-located.

#### Skills

Agile Pair Programming, TDD, Kanban, Sprints, Retros, Measure to iterate.

Languages Typescript, JavaScript ES5/ES6, JSX, HTML, CSS, Less/Sass, Node, NoSQL, SQL, Bash, Terraform.

**Libraries** React, React Native, Styled-Components, Redux, Jest, Mocha, Backbone, jQuery, Express, Koa, Underscore/Lodash, Handlebars, Jade, Moment, Numeral, Bootstrap, AWS, MongoDb, MySQL, PostGres, Redis, Webpack, Parcel.

Tools Webstorm, VSCode, Sketch, Photoshop, Slack, Asana, Jira, Miro, Browserstack, Looker, MixPanel, Segment, StatHat, DataDog, Rollbar, CircleCi, TeamViewer.

## **Employment**

## Senior Software Engineer @ Triptease

(contractor) April 2016 - April 2020

- Helped build a service to collect prices from online travel agents in realtime and handle over 100s of requests a minute. It used several strategies to avoid bot detection like auto IP pooling and full browser emulation.
- Deployed a performant service to automate clients brands (colours, style, fonts), used in the platform and by internal teams. It implemented an immutable database to have a built-in history of changes and deployed behind a CDN for performance.
- Built widgets that run on clients sites in isolation, i.e. it couldn't mutate or effect host sites. These widgets delivered a rich
  experience to our client's guests and help deliver uplift to their sales.
- Help build Triptease's platform dashboards used by clients to set up and maintain their suite of products. From performance dashboards to rich content editors and basic settings pages.

#### React Native Mobile App @ SC Field Guide

https://apple.co/2JJTjlc January 2016

• Built a React Native mobile app for a highly anticipated game, Star Citizen. The app provided players with information about ships in the game. At its peak, it had over 3k active monthly users.

#### Fullstack Developer @ Prism Digital

(contractor) July 2015 - Sept 2015

- Hosted clients main site as well as a Job board for candidates to search for roles. It was connected to an external job aggregator called BroadBean via a public API.
- Stack used Node, Express, Jade, and MongoDB. And used JSDocs to generate clear API docs from inline comments.

#### **Head of Development @ Boppl**

April 2013 - April 2016

- Managed a small team a people to deliver a mobile ordering platform. The team consisted of 1 iOS dev, 1 Android dev, 2 Java backend devs and 1 frontend dev which was me.
- Built a full CMS for managing products, stocks, and accounts. Using Backbone, jQuery, Handlebars, and Require.js.

## Education

- 1st Class Hons (BSc) in Computer Games Design 2005 2008 Staffordshire University
- MongoDB Certified Certificate 2015 MongoDB University

### Languages

Native English Speaker and learning German